<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Melissa K. Spencer</title>
    <link>https://melissakspencer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Melissa K. Spencer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/covid-dv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/covid-dv/</guid>
      <description>Around the world, news outlets have reported increases in domestic violence (DV) as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic and the attendant restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity. Although there are several reasons to expect that DV would increase for married and cohabiting couples, there are also forces that could reduce DV, such as COVID-19 sickness in a household or less time spent together by couples that live apart. It is also likely that victims who wish to report their abusers or seek assistance will face further barriers during the pandemic, which would depress reporting rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasers and Fatal Police Encounters</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/tasers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/tasers/</guid>
      <description>There are over 1,000 fatal police encounters per year in the United States, and an estimated 28,000 people have died during encounters with law enforcement since the year 2000. To decrease fatal encounters, police have sought weapons which can safely incapacitate people while they are taken into custody. One such weapon is the Conducted Energy Device (CED), better known by the brand name Taser. This research evaluates the effect of Tasers on fatal police encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maternal Inputs and Abortion Restrictions</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</guid>
      <description>In this paper we exploit variation in state-level abortion legislation to identify the effect of restrictions on maternal inputs and infant outcomes. We consider four restrictions: requirements for abortion counseling, mandated waiting periods between counseling and abortion procedures, parental involvement laws, and whether public funding for abortion is available through the state’s Medicaid program. We have compiled a novel dataset of state laws between 1990 and 2016 describing all four types of abortion restrictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safer Sex?</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/safer-sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/safer-sex/</guid>
      <description>The advent of the AIDS epidemic in the 1980s dramatically increased the cost of contracting a sexually transmitted infection (STI). Prior research shows that people responded to the AIDS epidemic by switching to sexual behaviors and contraceptive methods with lower likelihood of AIDS transmission. These behavioral adjustments also affect the likelihood of pregnancy and the incidence of other STIs. This paper provides the first evidence that the AIDS epidemic increased the birth rate and decreased the gonorrhea rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A published paper</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/published-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/published-paper/</guid>
      <description>Abstract</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resource/</guid>
      <description>A resource and some info about it</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>