<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gender Economics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/gender/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/gender/</guid><description>The transformation of women’s lives in the past century is among the most significant and far-reaching social and economic phenomenon, affecting not only women, but also their partners, their children, and society as a whole. In both developed and developing countries, women are acquiring more education, marrying later, having fewer children and spending a far greater fraction of their adult lives in the labor force. While women are catching up to men in many economic outcomes, persistent differences remain, particularly in occupational distributions and earnings.</description></item><item><title>Principles of Microeconomics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/principles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/principles/</guid><description>This course will introduce you to the fundamental questions, concepts, and techniques used in the study of economics. As an introduction to microeconomics, this course is focused primarily on understanding how individual economic agents (individual people, households, and businesses) make decisions. Students will gain insights into the ways that markets function, the role of government in markets, and some of the limitations of market-based analysis. Students will learn to apply economic concepts and models to discussions of current issues, and will also be introduced to the wide variety of topics that can be studied with economics.</description></item><item><title>Economics of Risky Behaviors</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/riskybehaviors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/riskybehaviors/</guid><description>This course provides a non-technical introduction to the economics of risky behaviors, including crime, alcohol and drug use, risky sexual behavior, and risky health behaviors. Students will learn basic economic concepts and gain insight into the wide range of topics that can be studied with a degree in economics. This course is ideal for introductory level students who are considering a major or minor in economics.</description></item><item><title>Intermediate Microeconomics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/intermicro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/intermicro/</guid><description>In this course you will learn to use economic models to analyze consumer and producer choices. Intermediate Microeconomics is a core course for the Economics major. My goal in this course is to prepare you for 4000-level economics courses by teaching you to use the standard tools of economic analysis. As such, this course is skills-based: the best way to succeed and prepare for exams is to solve practice problems.</description></item><item><title>Safer Sex?</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/safer-sex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/safer-sex/</guid><description>Behavioral adjustments to mitigate increasing risk of STIs can increase or decrease the likelihood of pregnancy. This paper measures the effects of the arrival and spread of AIDS across U.S. cities in the 1980s and 1990s on births and abortions. I show that the AIDS epidemic increased the birth rate by 0.55 percent and the abortion rate by 1.77 percent. I find support for two underlying mechanisms to explain the increase in pregnancies.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-cities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-cities/</guid><description>We empirically investigate the impact of COVID-19 shutdowns on domestic violence using incident-level data on both domestic-related calls for service and crime reports of domestic violence assaults from the 18 major US police departments for which both types of records are available. Although we confirm prior reports of an increase in domestic calls for service at the start of the pandemic, we find that the increase preceded mandatory shutdowns, and there was an incremental decline following the government imposition of restrictions.</description></item><item><title>Themes for Principles of Microeconomics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/themes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/themes/</guid><description>Paper(coming soon) with Erik Craft and Maia Linask:
This paper describes a new approach to increasing content relevance and student engagement in Principles of Microeconomics by organizing the class around a cohesive theme. While continuing to teach students standard introductory material, we use supplementary readings, assignments, and examples throughout the semester that are related to a specific topic. Themed sections for Principles of Microeconomics were piloted at University of Richmond in Fall 2022 and Spring 2023 on the topics of crime, inequality, dating, and globalization.</description></item><item><title>Economics Writing Guide</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/writingguide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/writingguide/</guid><description>I created this writing guide for students in my Principles of Microeconomics class. This guide is designed to help students better understand what is expected for economics writing assignments and to help them improve their writing. I plan to update this guide in Spring 2022 with an annotated sample essay.</description></item><item><title>Abortion Counseling Laws</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</guid><description>Nearly two-thirds of states have abortion counseling laws requiring that women receive and acknowledge state-mandated information prior to giving their informed consent for abortion. The mandated information varies widely across states and may include scientifically inaccurate statements regarding the risks of abortion, illustrations of fetuses, or ultrasound requirements. Despite the ubiquity of these laws, little is known about the effect of counseling laws on women’s abortion decisions and birth rates. We compile a novel dataset of state-level abortion counseling laws and define a classification system for these laws, including fetal-focused counseling, risk-focused counseling, ultrasound requirements, and ultrasound display requirements.</description></item><item><title>Gender Economics Teaching Network</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/teachingnetwork/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/teachingnetwork/</guid><description>This network is designed to aid instructors in preparing and teaching gender economics courses in order to give students a more diverse and research-oriented learning experience. There are three components, all of which are voluntary for those wishing to participate:
A Dropbox folder where instructors can share course materials, slides for research papers on gender topics, and book suggestions for gender economics courses. A Google Spreadsheet where instructors can request to be added to the email list for Zoom social hours, request to be added to the Dropbox folder, and indicate their willingness to swap lectures with other instructors.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence in LA</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-la/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-la/</guid><description>Around the world, policymakers and news reports warned that the COVID-19 pandemic, and attendant restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity, could lead to a surge in domestic violence (DV). Some prominent initial studies of the effects of the pandemic showed evidence of greater DV incidence, but findings were inconsistent across locations and DV measures. This paper focuses on a single major city, Los Angeles, to measure the impact of the initial pandemic shutdown on three DV measures based on police data (911 calls, crime incidents, and arrests) as well as measures based on two non-police administrative sources (the county DV hotline and hospital records).</description></item></channel></rss>