<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/</link><description>Recent content on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gender Economics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/gender/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/gender/</guid><description>&lt;p>The transformation of women’s lives in the past century is among the most significant and far-reaching social and economic phenomenon, affecting not only women, but also their partners, their children, and society as a whole. In both developed and developing countries, women are acquiring more education, marrying later, having fewer children and spending a far greater fraction of their adult lives in the labor force. While women are catching up to men in many economic outcomes, persistent differences remain, particularly in occupational distributions and earnings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Principles of Microeconomics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/principles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/principles/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course will introduce you to the fundamental questions, concepts, and techniques used in the study of economics. As an introduction to microeconomics, this course is focused primarily on understanding how individual economic agents (individual people, households, and businesses) make decisions. Students will gain insights into the ways that markets function, the role of government in markets, and some of the limitations of market-based analysis. Students will learn to apply economic concepts and models to discussions of current issues, and will also be introduced to the wide variety of topics that can be studied with economics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Economics of Risky Behaviors</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/riskybehaviors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/riskybehaviors/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course provides a non-technical introduction to the economics of risky behaviors, including
crime, alcohol and drug use, risky sexual behavior, and risky health behaviors. Students will learn
basic economic concepts and gain insight into the wide range of topics that can be studied with
a degree in economics. This course is ideal for introductory level students who are considering a
major or minor in economics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intermediate Microeconomics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/intermicro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/teaching/courses/intermicro/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this course you will learn to use economic models to analyze consumer and producer
choices. Intermediate Microeconomics is a core course for the Economics major. My goal
in this course is to prepare you for 4000-level economics courses by teaching you to use
the standard tools of economic analysis. As such, this course is skills-based: the best way
to succeed and prepare for exams is to solve practice problems.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>