<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COVID19 on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/tags/covid19/</link><description>Recent content in COVID19 on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/tags/covid19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-cities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-cities/</guid><description>We empirically investigate the impact of COVID-19 shutdowns on domestic violence using incident-level data on both domestic-related calls for service and crime reports of domestic violence assaults from the 18 major US police departments for which both types of records are available. Although we confirm prior reports of an increase in domestic calls for service at the start of the pandemic, we find that the increase preceded mandatory shutdowns, and there was an incremental decline following the government imposition of restrictions.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence in LA</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dv-la/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dv-la/</guid><description>Around the world, policymakers and news reports have warned that domestic violence (DV) could increase as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic and the attendant restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity. However, both anecdotal accounts and academic research have found inconsistent effects of the pandemic on DV across measures and cities. We use highfrequency, real-time data from Los Angeles on 911 calls, crime incidents, arrests, and calls to a DV hotline to study the effects of COVID-19 shutdowns on DV.</description></item></channel></rss>