<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Teaching on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/tags/teaching/</link><description>Recent content in Teaching on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Themes for Principles of Microeconomics</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/themes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/themes/</guid><description>Paper(coming soon) with Erik Craft and Maia Linask:
This paper describes a new approach to increasing content relevance and student engagement in Principles of Microeconomics by organizing the class around a cohesive theme. While continuing to teach students standard introductory material, we use supplementary readings, assignments, and examples throughout the semester that are related to a specific topic. Themed sections for Principles of Microeconomics were piloted at University of Richmond in Fall 2022 and Spring 2023 on the topics of crime, inequality, dating, and globalization.</description></item><item><title>Gender Economics Teaching Network</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/teachingnetwork/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/resources/resourcedocs/teachingnetwork/</guid><description>This network is designed to aid instructors in preparing and teaching gender economics courses in order to give students a more diverse and research-oriented learning experience. There are three components, all of which are voluntary for those wishing to participate:
A Dropbox folder where instructors can share course materials, slides for research papers on gender topics, and book suggestions for gender economics courses. A Google Spreadsheet where instructors can request to be added to the email list for Zoom social hours, request to be added to the Dropbox folder, and indicate their willingness to swap lectures with other instructors.</description></item></channel></rss>