<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>In Progress on Melissa K. Spencer</title>
    <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in In Progress on Melissa K. Spencer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasers and Fatal Police Encounters</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/tasers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/tasers/</guid>
      <description>There are over 1,000 fatal police encounters per year in the United States, and an estimated 28,000 people have died during encounters with law enforcement since the year 2000. To decrease fatal encounters, police have sought weapons which can safely incapacitate people while they are taken into custody. One such weapon is the Conducted Energy Device (CED), better known by the brand name Taser. This research evaluates the effect of Tasers on fatal police encounters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abortion Counseling Laws</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</guid>
      <description>Nearly two-thirds of states have abortion counseling laws requiring that women receive and acknowledge state-mandated information prior to giving their informed consent for abortion. The mandated information varies widely across states, and may include scientifically inaccurate statements regarding the risks of abortion, illustrations of fetuses, or ultrasound requirements. Despite the ubiquity of these laws, little is known about the effect of counseling laws on women’s abortion decision and birth rates. Using a novel dataset of state-level abortion counseling laws, we find that counseling laws that contain ultrasound requirements increase the birth rate to white women by as much as 1 birth per 1,000 women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/covid-dv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/covid-dv/</guid>
      <description>Around the world, news outlets have reported increases in domestic violence (DV) as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic and the attendant restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity. Although there are several reasons to expect that DV would increase for married and cohabiting couples, there are also forces that could reduce DV, such as COVID-19 sickness in a household or less time spent together by couples that live apart. It is also likely that victims who wish to report their abusers or seek assistance will face further barriers during the pandemic, which would depress reporting rates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>