<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Domestic Violence on Melissa K. Spencer</title>
    <link>https://melissakspencer.com/tags/domestic-violence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Domestic Violence on Melissa K. Spencer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/tags/domestic-violence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/covid-dv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/covid-dv/</guid>
      <description>Around the world, news outlets have reported increases in domestic violence (DV) as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic and the attendant restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity. Although there are several reasons to expect that DV would increase for married and cohabiting couples, there are also forces that could reduce DV, such as COVID-19 sickness in a household or less time spent together by couples that live apart. It is also likely that victims who wish to report their abusers or seek assistance will face further barriers during the pandemic, which would depress reporting rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence</title>
      <link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dv-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dv-la/</guid>
      <description>Around the world, policymakers and news reports have conveyed concern that domestic violence (DV) increased as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic and the attendant restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity. However, both anecdotal accounts and academic research have found inconsistent effects of the pandemic on DV across measures and cities. We use high-frequency, real-time data from Los Angeles on 911 calls, crime incidents, arrests, and calls to a DV hotline to identify variation across multiple measures from the same population.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>