<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fertility on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/tags/fertility/</link><description>Recent content in Fertility on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/tags/fertility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Safer Sex?</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/safer-sex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/safer-sex/</guid><description>Behavioral adjustments to mitigate increasing risk of STIs can increase or decrease the likelihood of pregnancy. This paper measures the effects of the arrival and spread of AIDS across U.S. cities in the 1980s and 1990s on births and abortions. I show that the AIDS epidemic increased the birth rate by 0.55 percent and the abortion rate by 1.77 percent. I find support for two underlying mechanisms to explain the increase in pregnancies.</description></item><item><title>Abortion Counseling Laws</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</guid><description>Nearly two-thirds of states have abortion counseling laws requiring that women receive and acknowledge state-mandated information prior to giving their informed consent for abortion. The mandated information varies widely across states and may include scientifically inaccurate statements regarding the risks of abortion, illustrations of fetuses, or ultrasound requirements. Despite the ubiquity of these laws, little is known about the effect of counseling laws on women’s abortion decisions and birth rates. We compile a novel dataset of state-level abortion counseling laws and define a classification system for these laws, including fetal-focused counseling, risk-focused counseling, ultrasound requirements, and ultrasound display requirements.</description></item></channel></rss>