<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Working Papers on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/</link><description>Recent content in Working Papers on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Abortion Ballot Measures</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dobbs-voting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dobbs-voting/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the 2022 U.S. midterm elections, Democratic candidates lost fewer than predicted seats and stymied an expected red wave. News coverage and polling data represent this surprise Democratic success as a result of voters’ response to the Supreme Court overturning Roe v. Wade. Using county-level vote data, we find that the decrease in Republican vote margin in 2022 can be explained by demographic and economic factors. However, relative to the national average, the Republican vote margin decreased by 4.8 percentage points more in states with abortion-related ballot measures. Our results indicate that abortion ballot measures have effects on election outcomes of a magnitude large enough to determine competitive races.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Themes in Principles</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/themes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/themes/</guid><description>&lt;p>This paper describes a new, low-cost approach to increasing content relevance and student engagement in Principles of Microeconomics by organizing the class around a cohesive theme. While continuing to teach students standard introductory material, we use supplementary readings, assignments, and examples throughout the semester that are related to a specific topic. Instructors at the University of Richmond piloted themed sections for Principles of Microeconomics in Fall 2022 and Spring 2023 on the topics of crime, inequality, dating, and globalization. In this paper, we provide an overview of our approach, including the institutional environment in which it was implemented, examples of how we related the themes to economic principles, and instructor and student perceptions of the benefits and difficulties of themed classes. We also provide a general framework and guidance for other instructors to use when implementing themes.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>