<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Working Papers on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/</link><description>Recent content in Working Papers on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Safer Sex?</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/safer-sex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/safer-sex/</guid><description>The emergence of AIDS in the 1980s dramatically increased the cost of contracting a sexually transmitted infection (STI). Prior research shows that people responded to the AIDS epidemic by switching to sexual behaviors and contraceptive methods with lower likelihood of AIDS transmission. These behavioral adjustments also affect the likelihood of pregnancy and the incidence of other STIs. This paper provides the first evidence that the AIDS epidemic in the United States increased the birth rate and the abortion rate, and decreased the gonorrhea rate.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence in LA</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dv-la/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dv-la/</guid><description>Around the world, policymakers and news reports have warned that domestic violence (DV) could increase as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic and the attendant restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity. However, both anecdotal accounts and academic research have found inconsistent effects of the pandemic on DV across measures and cities. We use highfrequency, real-time data from Los Angeles on 911 calls, crime incidents, arrests, and calls to a DV hotline to study the effects of COVID-19 shutdowns on DV.</description></item></channel></rss>