<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Crime on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/tags/crime/</link><description>Recent content in Crime on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/tags/crime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence in US Cities</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-cities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-cities/</guid><description>&lt;p>We empirically investigate the impact of COVID-19 shutdowns on domestic violence using incident-level data on both domestic-related calls for service and crime reports of domestic violence assaults from the 18 major US police departments for which both types of records are available. Although we confirm prior reports of an increase in domestic calls for service at the start of the pandemic, we find that the increase preceded mandatory shutdowns, and there was an incremental decline following the government imposition of restrictions. We also find no evidence that domestic violence crimes increased. Rather, police reports of domestic violence assaults declined significantly during the initial shutdown period. There was no significant change in intimate partner homicides during shutdown months and victimization survey reports of intimate partner violence were lower. Our results fail to support claims that shutdowns increased domestic violence and suggest caution before drawing inference or basing policy solely on data from calls to police.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence in LA</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-la/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv-la/</guid><description>&lt;p>From the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic, policymakers and news reports warned that restrictions on individual mobility and commercial activity could lead to a surge in domestic violence (DV). Some initial studies found evidence of greater DV incidence during the pandemic, but findings were inconsistent across locations and DV measures. This paper focuses on a single major city, Los Angeles (LA), to study the impact of the initial pandemic shutdown. We use three DV measures from police data (911 calls, crime incidents and arrests) as well as two measures from non-police administrative sources (the county DV hotline and hospital records). We find an increase in DV calls to the police and calls to the hotline. However, we find that DV crimes recorded by police and hospital visits by female assault (and DV) victims decreased significantly, suggesting that the increase in calls came from higher reporting rates. The decrease in DV crimes is not attributable to reductions in policing intensity, as the arrest rate for DV crimes was higher during the shutdown. We conclude that the initial LA shutdown increased the rates at which people contacted authorities about DV, but decreased the overall incidence of physical DV crimes in the population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COVID-19 and Domestic Violence in the US</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv_chapter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/published/dv_chapter/</guid><description>&lt;p>This chapter examines the impact of COVID-19 shutdowns on domestic violence (DV) in the United States. Despite widespread concerns that pandemic shutdowns could increase DV, initial studies found mixed evidence that varied across data sources and locations. We review the evolving literature on the effects of the pandemic and highlight results from studies that examine multiple measures of DV across a common set of large cities. These studies show that the conflicting early results are due to opposite effects of pandemic shutdowns on two measures of DV in police data: an increase in domestic violence 911 calls and a decrease in DV crime reports. In theory, this divergence can come from either higher DV reporting rates, possibly because of additional media attention to DV and greater third-party calling, or from lower policing intensity for DV crimes. Prior evidence from police data and other sources supports the conclusion that the increase in calls came from greater reporting, while the incidence of criminal DV decreased. Finally, we present new evidence drawing on police and hospitals records from across the state of California to show that DV crimes and hospital emergency department (ED) visits were both lower during pandemic shutdowns. Appendix available &lt;a href="https://melissakspencer.com/Chenetal2025.pdf">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>