<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Abortion on Melissa K. Spencer</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/tags/abortion/</link><description>Recent content in Abortion on Melissa K. Spencer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melissakspencer.com/tags/abortion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Abortion Ballot Measures</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dobbs-voting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/dobbs-voting/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the 2022 U.S. midterm elections, Democratic candidates lost fewer than predicted seats and stymied an expected red wave. News coverage and polling data represent this surprise Democratic success as a result of voters’ response to the Supreme Court overturning Roe v. Wade. Using county-level vote data, we find that the decrease in Republican vote margin in 2022 can be explained by demographic and economic factors. However, relative to the national average, the Republican vote margin decreased by 4.8 percentage points more in states with abortion-related ballot measures. Our results indicate that abortion ballot measures have effects on election outcomes of a magnitude large enough to determine competitive races.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Themes in Principles</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/themes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/workingpapers/themes/</guid><description>&lt;p>This paper describes a new, low-cost approach to increasing content relevance and student engagement in Principles of Microeconomics by organizing the class around a cohesive theme. While continuing to teach students standard introductory material, we use supplementary readings, assignments, and examples throughout the semester that are related to a specific topic. Instructors at the University of Richmond piloted themed sections for Principles of Microeconomics in Fall 2022 and Spring 2023 on the topics of crime, inequality, dating, and globalization. In this paper, we provide an overview of our approach, including the institutional environment in which it was implemented, examples of how we related the themes to economic principles, and instructor and student perceptions of the benefits and difficulties of themed classes. We also provide a general framework and guidance for other instructors to use when implementing themes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Abortion Counseling Laws</title><link>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melissakspencer.com/research/inprogress/abortion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nearly two-thirds of states have abortion counseling laws requiring that women receive and acknowledge state-mandated information prior to giving their informed consent for abortion. The mandated information varies widely across states and may include scientifically inaccurate statements regarding the risks of abortion, illustrations of fetuses, or ultrasound requirements. Despite the ubiquity of these laws, little is known about the effect of counseling laws on women’s abortion decisions and birth rates. We compile a novel dataset of state-level abortion counseling laws and define a classification system for these laws, including fetal-focused counseling, risk-focused counseling, ultrasound requirements, and ultrasound display requirements. Using this novel dataset, we analyze the effect of abortion counseling laws on county-level birth rates. We find evidence that counseling laws affect birth rates, and show that effects are heterogeneous across type of counseling law as well as demographic groups.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>